Good evening, teachers, colleagues, and experts.
Good evening, I am Yang Xue Mei, a teacher at Huizhou Academy.
Tonight, I will talk about the situation of our digital technology in the construction process of our workshop.
First of all, I would like to say that our Fashion Digital Art Creative Time Workshop was established in 2009.
It is based in Huizhou Academy, Xuzhi Guangdong Fashion Academy.
It is a practical innovation platform that integrates fashion, digitalization, teaching, research and education into one.
At the same time, the teaching team of our workshop is also a provincial teaching team.
When we were building such a workshop, it was designed according to the professional direction of the clothing product process.
There are two teachers in each direction.
At the same time, we also added three teaching consultants.
So now the whole team consists of 24 people.
Among them,
there are eight businessmen in our teaching team.
Our turnover is 6 billion yuan.
Professor Fu accounts for almost 50%.
So overall, we are still working towards a higher level.
This is basically a general outline.
In 2018, our workshop became the key platform construction unit in Guangdong Province.
In 2020, we won the Laomo and craftsman talent innovation workshop.
In 2021, we won the Laomo and craftsman innovation workshop of Guangdong Province.
At the same time, because our team consists of 76% of female teaching staff,
I have also applied to Guangdong Province and Huizhou City for a female staff innovation workshop.
Also, our fashion, digital art and creative practice workshop was established in 2018.
Last year, we won the second prize in the first competition in Guangdong Province.
This is the overall result and situation.
These are some of the stages of our years.
Among them, what we should mention is that
in terms of social training,
we have a Laomo workshop activity.
Although during the pandemic,
we have hosted 38 events so far.
We have served more than 2,000 people.
Because of the pandemic,
our activities are restricted every time.
This platform has done a lot of application development on digital technology.
Let's take a look at a social effect first.
I will show you the good points of our platform first.
That is, we have developed 10 virtual systems together.
One of the systems is the
Fashion, Fabric, Pattern, Creative, and Appliance Virtual Formatting Experiment.
This has been recommended by the Guangdong Provincial Education Hall
as a national first-class formatting course in early this year.
This system has also become one of the competitive test systems
for the comprehensive training and comprehensive ability of college students in the whole country.
Now more than 50 colleges and thousands of students are using it.
At the same time, it has also become one of the top test systems in the whole country in 2022.
The program is called the
Transformation of the Future of Education and Education,
which is a virtual formatting experiment teaching and quality sharing project.
We have worked on some teaching reforms.
Many times in the Tencent News,
the Southern Urban News,
and other media reports.
Among them,
the article is recommended by the Huizhou Academy for the Promotion of Education,
Cooperation and Cooperation,
and Cooperation with New Energy.
We officially started in 2021
in the direction of fashion design and engineering internal clothes professionalization,
which was announced in 2008.
But so far,
we have basically seen from zero
that we are one of the leading companies in the country.
To do this,
I would like to communicate with you today.
Digital technology has been integrated into our entire clothing education system
during our entire growth process.
Let's first carry out a composition analysis of the clothing education system.
It has teachers, students, and courses and environments.
So we will integrate digital technology into the entire process.
The teacher is in the process of implementing his teaching concept today.
The tools and materials he needs,
including textbooks, experimental environments,
and his teaching resources,
all need to be integrated into this concept of virtual technology.
Finally,
it forms a teaching and learning method with experience as a feature,
so that students can find the way they like in such an environment.
This is our overall structural design at that time.
In the process of doing that,
we will,
especially in the textbook part,
we have different directions according to the industry.
We have,
for example,
the setting of 10 textbooks,
as well as the setting of virtual environments.
However, in the textbook,
we have set up some content,
especially the AR code.
We use the app system,
that is,
with the support of network technology,
we let the information of our paper textbooks
become vivid,
and its knowledge
is constantly increasing with the expansion of the outside world,
the outside factories,
and the outside technologies,
so that his textbook is no longer
a simple paper,
but a three-dimensional textbook.
Let's take a look at this situation now.
If the textbook is to be formed,
it must have a knowledge chain.
So when we started this kind of course
at the beginning of 2011,
we based on digital technology,
and then connected our knowledge chain with the industrial chain,
and formed our current knowledge system.
At the same time,
we formed what we see now,
such a three-dimensional,
innovative teaching theory model.
What does that mean?
That is to say,
the structure at the bottom
is set according to the industrialization of the course.
The corresponding teaching team
is also set according to the industrialization.
The teacher inside will have materials,
will have craftsmanship,
design,
sales,
display,
paper,
structure,
all of them.
So in this setting process,
we will set up the teacher
and the entire textbook.
At this time,
we will apply our virtual digital technology
to our real textbooks,
to our laboratories.
Then we also built for the students,
there are websites,
there are our corresponding operating systems,
as well as our virtual experiments,
as well as our AIV system,
as well as our learning system.
Open to the whole,
create such an environment for the students.
And the students in this environment,
they are cooperating in a group.
Because each of our students,
he has his own preferences,
he may not work according to our direction.
That is,
what content do you set up?
What does he have to learn?
This is what we think again.
We hope that the students can find
what they like.
And because of such a teaching theory,
when we were in the fourth and sixth years,
our teaching results
respectively won the first prize
in the Huizhou City Teaching Achievement Award.
You can take a look at
the series of focus on the production
and operation of industrial products
built with this digital technology.
Of these four books,
they have all been published.
Each of these books
has an app.
What does it mean?
That is,
we can take a look at
a book.
Let's make the content of this book
three-dimensional.
How to make it three-dimensional?
Let's take a look at the video.
1.
Thank you.
What does this mean?
It's all the pictures in our guidebook.
Students can scan through their phones.
After scanning,
there will be corresponding other knowledge.
For example,
the clothes you are looking at now can be three-dimensional and wearable.
At the same time,
you can also adjust the color of the clothes,
add the patterns,
and redesign the style.
This way,
students will be able to apply it better.
In addition,
there is also a program for this style.
It's called
artificial intelligence.
Its structural analysis can also be found in virtual systems.
When students get such a book,
they can use their phones to search for it at any time based on their questions.
This is the state in which we combine virtual technology with our current paper textbooks.
In 2021,
we also conducted some scientific research on these results.
We are also leading in China.
In terms of the experimental part,
we will apply digital technology in different areas in different professional directions.
For example,
we have developed 10 systems for our design,
engineering,
and performance directions.
In other words,
a costume will need to have a design,
engineering,
and later display
from the very beginning of its construction to its final product.
So we have conducted a virtual system demonstration in accordance with the professional settings in our school.
Strictly speaking,
to strengthen students' understanding of the style structure, fabric, pattern, and color in the history of internal clothing development.
Students can use materials from different eras in the experiment to design internal clothing products with a specific style of the era.
The experiment solved the problems of art and technology that are difficult to integrate in traditional clothing and design teaching theory,
and provided a way for theoretical knowledge to be quickly transformed into design practice,
and inspired students to explore and develop new styles and new thoughts based on historical knowledge.
This is the virtual part.
In 2022, our results were approved by the provincial level,
and the results were approved by the domestic advanced level.
Of course, during the approval process, there were textbooks, supporting education, and our teaching methods,
as well as some of our supporting systems and teaching resources.
Our school has a virtual exhibition system for students' works,
as well as our internal clothing virtual museum.
These are all part of the construction of our library.
Students can enter such a system through their mobile phones,
and can check out their previous senior and senior design works at any time.
For students, this has played a more important role in building the library.
Just now, I briefly talked about the construction of our digital technology in our current workshop.
This is just one example.
I would like to share with you today
how our students are using these systems,
and how we are doing the overall planning.
Let's take a look at the data first.
This data shows the direction of high school graduates in 2023.
In fact, this data is relatively high.
It was 57.6% in 2023.
It was still low before.
In other words, the direction of students after graduation,
even after graduation,
is less than 60%.
The remaining 40% of students are doing something else.
Of course, they may continue to build.
But from the perspective of five to ten years,
many of our students are no longer doing their professional work.
So as a high school teacher,
I will no longer focus on the construction of professional knowledge as before,
but rather put the construction of professional knowledge on the virtual platform we just saw.
On the website platform,
in the app system of every textbook.
We will put it in there.
In fact, let students know more about what they like.
Create an environment for students.
This is the education that I understand.
It should return to people.
How do we do it?
This is what I want to communicate with you.
When we started our professional teaching reform from 2011,
the concept of teaching just now
has been integrated into our entire education system.
So we have established an industrialized education team.
The main goal is to let students cooperate in a group
to learn their courses.
And our model is just like the model you see on the screen now.
We have all the teachers who design, design, process, manage, and demonstrate
to intervene in the learning of all knowledge
from a student's entrepreneurship to product process.
In the implementation process,
some students may like design.
Some students may like craftsmanship.
They combine themselves.
Of course, in the process of combining,
we have some requirements.
Students circulate through their design works for four years.
Because we follow a professional direction.
So our profession is divided into four directions.
Then let students cooperate with each other during this period.
Find what they like.
Form a cross-disciplinary teaching.
In the last semester,
we also passed the test.
Let students learn,
use,
and integrate.
In other words,
let students do it in the mode of an entrepreneurial company.
Using these two methods,
there is actually only one goal.
This goal is for students to find what they like to do.
Only if they like it,
they can implement it in the actual course.
And then sell their ideas as products
to the customers they think.
This increases the professional ability of students
and the creative ability of students.
In fact, it really allows students to find
what they like to do.
I think from this perspective,
they can do what they want to do.
Then they can have a better environment
to work in the future society.
This is my perception.
This is also a practice process
from 2011 to now.
In this 13-year practice process,
we also formed a model.
That is to say, teaching,
students,
and enterprises.
These three points form a turning point.
For example,
our students now have a team of entrepreneurs.
All the digital technologies in the textbooks
that you just saw,
including all the modeling used in our virtual system,
are all used in the Colour system.
So in this system environment,
we let students do these corresponding projects.
In fact, they are not done by teachers,
but by our entrepreneurial student team.
Students guide students,
brothers and sisters.
In this way,
it is easier for students
to get close to what they want,
and to promote what they want.
So our entire teaching team
only needs to promote
teaching, students, and enterprises.
This is a starting point.
Then students will be able to move.
And these students,
in two years,
and five students,
formed a technology company
together in Huizhou.
When they reach this state,
they will be able to promote teaching.
Because this model has also been formed,
so in the process of
the construction of the workshop,
students can have these four directions
to assist our entire teaching.
Four directions.
Then the interaction of teaching
and the growth of teaching
are formed.
Our students can be in the second grade,
the third grade,
and they can be involved in our entire project.
In the fourth grade,
they can go to the enterprise,
and they can really feel
some of the work of the enterprise,
which is close to them
during the school period.
At the same time,
if they are willing to start their own business,
they can start their own business
with their seniors.
So now we have basically formed
such a closed learning system
of anti-improvement teaching.
At the same time,
our students,
because they formed
such a professional
entrepreneurship company
during the school period,
so they also helped us
in some things
in the teaching process.
For example,
in recent years,
students,
if they participate
in the student platform,
there are 30 to 40 of them.
The statistics are
in 2022.
So in the last four years,
we now have
160 students
trained in this workshop.
What does this mean?
It means that
our modeling technology
just now
has 160 people
trained in this.
80 of them
have entered
the relevant enterprise
to work.
And five students
stayed in the school
and formed
such a school-level
cooperative enterprise.
Then they also
participated in our project
and also had
14 technical standards.
These are all
in our
books
and in the virtual system.
It has played
a very big role.
At the same time,
because these students
helped teach,
so the students
in the process
of communicating with them
do not need
teachers to intervene.
There is no direct arrangement
between these teachers
and students,
but the communication
between students
and students.
So the students
will do this
one-to-one
and bring them
to the experiment
of the teacher,
and then
continue to start a business,
improving
the students'
practical skills.
This data
is basically
the situation
of some projects
in various directions
in the past few years,
that is,
some data
on the business
of college students.
This is
mutual.
Because
we are now
in the process
of teaching,
scientific research
and our students'
entrepreneurship
are all
integrated together.
So
our teaching
is very good
and has such
a good result.
At the same time,
the students
have this effect.
This effect
is very obvious.
Because you see,
they are a company
established in 2020.
So far,
the companies
cooperating with them,
the universities cooperating with them,
including our school,
now there are five courses
that they take
to teach students.
This does not need
the teacher to do it again.
Of course,
this part of the class
is all based on
our 3D modeling
to do the
procrastination course.
Finally,
what I want to tell you
is that
in the entire
time working room
in the course of education,
the teacher
will integrate
your teaching
research
with the students.
The teaching
will also come out.
And in terms of
our school cooperation,
we do not
rely on the company
to decide
what this person
should want.
Instead,
we return to
our own teaching
perspective
to return the education
to the person
and let the teaching
understand
and let the students
adapt
and look for
and improve
their own interests
and hobbies.
So
students
in the future
will be
the students
who really
want to
work in the business.
So,
I think
through
the course of
teaching
in the workshop
for so many years,
we basically
achieved
what I
hope
our students
can achieve
the most.
That's
all
I have
to share
today.
Thank you,
everyone.